Raymond, Eleanor. The Eleanor Raymond Collection: An Inventory.
Eleanor Raymond Collection.
- Series A / Project Files, A000
  - Project Files: Walworth House Alterations, / Date(s): 1948; : A4806
  - Project Files: Stackpole House, / Date(s): 1948; : A4809
    Note: Project files related to Stackpole House, 56 Morton Road, Milton, MA. Flat roof scheme; open plan; cinder block.
  - Project Files: Peabody Garage, / Date(s): 1948; : A4811
    Note: Project files related to Peabody Garage, Newbury Street, Boston, MA. This is a spraybooth.
    Content: Drawings from #6311 mis-filed here.
  - Project Files: Bass-Perkins Residential Alterations, / Date(s): 1948; : A4813
    Content: Mis-filed contour map, J.W. Steel property, Concord, MA, 1948.
  - Project Files: Peabody Border House, / Date(s): 1948-1950, 1955; : A4814
    Note: Project files related to Border House (known as Peabody Border House), Dover, MA. Hope's steel windows; vertical siding; almost flat roof.
    Note: Located near Sun House. Radiant heating system.
  - Project Files: Close House Renovations, / Date(s): 1949; : A4817
    Note: Project file related to work undertaken at Dublin, NH.
  - Project Files: Power Ltd. Projects, / Date(s): 1953-1954; : A4902
    Note: Project file related to work undertaken at Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: Blewer House, / Date(s): 1949, 1961-1962; : A4903
    Note: Project files related to Blewer House, Sugar Hill, New Hampshire. Drawings on vellum.
  - Project Files: Conant House Alteration, / Date(s): 1949; : A4907
    Note: Correspondence file only; no associated drawing file.
  - Project Files: WKNE, / Date(s): 1950; : A4908
    Content: Blueprint of 1945 design by Parker, Clinch, Crimp, Architects.
  - Project Files: Pope House, / Date(s): 1949-1950; : A4911
    Content: Flat files contain 23 b&w mounted and unmounted photographs: 17 - 8" x 10" by Vaughan's, 21 Vestry, Beverly. 1 color 8" x 10". 1 negative 8" x 10".
    Published in: Published in D. Cole; Architectural Record, 113 (January 1953), "Weekend Residence of R.L. Pope, Smith's Point, Manchester-By-The-Sea, Massachusetts, 137-139.
  - Project Files: Parker Farmhouse Alterations, / Date(s): 1949; : A4914
    Note: Project file related to work undertaken at Claremont, MA.
  - Project Files: Bradley House Renovations, / Date(s): 1952; : A4918
    Note: Project files related to Bradley House, Pohrapoag, MA. Detailing; use of plastic.
  - Project Files: Cabot House Alterations, / Date(s): 1949-1950; : A4919
    Note: Project files related to Cabot House Alterations, Manchester, MA. Detailing.
    Content: Blueprint of original house drawings by Dodge, Architect. Calls client "Abbott".
  - Project Files: MacLeish Garden, / Date(s): 1949; : A4920
    Note: Project files related to MacLeish Garden, 9 Louisburg Square, Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: F.H.A. Minimum Sun-Heated House, / Date(s): 1950; : A4921
  - Project Files: Whiting House, / Date(s): 1950; : A5002
    Note: Project files related to Whiting House, Tyler Road, Belmont, MA.
  - Project Files: Osgood House Alterations, / Date(s): 1950; : A5010
    Note: Location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Atkinson House Alterations, / Date(s): 1949-1951; : A5013
    Note: Project files related to Atkinson House Alterations. Extensively drawn and detailed.
    Content: Box #1 contains 2 - 3" x 5" color photographs, mounted.
  - Project Files: Donovan House, / Date(s): 1950; : A5014
    Note: Project files related to Donovan House, Eastern Point Road, Gloucester, MA. Fenestration: cinder block. Also spelled Donnovan.
  - Project Files: Robinson House, / Date(s): 1950; : A5015
    Note: Project files related to Robinson Garage Cottage, East Gloucester, MA.
    Note: This is an addition to an existing garage. Blueprint of design from Phillips & Holloran shows superiority of ER design.
  - Project Files: Paine House Alterations, / Date(s): 1951; : A5018
    Note: Project files related to Paine House Alterations, 45 Jefferson Road, Chestnut Hill, Brookline, MA.
  - Project Files: Doriot House, / Date(s): 1956; : A5019
    Note: Project file related to Doriot House.
  - Project Files: Warner House, / Date(s): 1951; : A5101
    Note: Project files related to Warner House, Argilla Road, Ipswich, MA. Plans for a "simple" house. Plans for a "transitional" garden.
    Content: Correspondence File contains yellow trace sketch.
  - Project Files: Fall Garage Remodeling, / Date(s): 1951; : A5102
    Note: Project file related to Fall garage project; location unknown.
  - Project Files: Peck House Remodeling, / Date(s): 1951; : A5103
    Note: Project file related to Peck house, Cambridge, MA.
  - Project Files: Penthouse Addition to Townhouse, / Date(s): 1951-1952; : A5105
    Note: Project files related to Penthouse Addition to Townhouse, 112 Pinckney Street (Pinckney Street & Embankment Road), Boston, MA. Use of Panelwall system with honeycomb construction. Aluminum windows.
  - Project Files: Power Ltd. Exhibits, / Date(s): 1951, 1959; : A5106
    Note: Project files related to Power Ltd. Exhibits, Architectural Center, Boston, (1951); Boston Art Museum, Boston, (1959), MA.
  - Project Files: Orchard School Landscaping, / Date(s): 1951; : A5107
    Note: Project file related to landscaping of Watertown, MA's Orchard School.
  - Project Files: Crotched Mountain Rehabilitation Center House, / Date(s): 1951; : A5108
    Note: Adden, Parker, Clinch & Crimp, State Street, Boston, MA [architects].
  - Project Files: Cabot Barn Addition, / Date(s): 1951; : A5109
    Note: Project file related to Cabot Barn; location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Peck House Alteration, / Date(s): 1951; : A5111
    Note: Project file related to Peck House; location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Richardson Furniture, / Date(s): 1950; : A5114
    Note: Project files related to Richardson Furniture. This is a dictionary stand.
  - Project Files: Moulton House, / Date(s): 1951, 1955; : A5115
    Note: Project related to Moulton House, Ashby, MA.
  - Project Files: Johnson House, / Date(s): 1951; : A5116
    Note: Project files related to Johnson House. Reminiscent of 1930 Belmont House.
  - Project Files: Wellman House Addition, / Date(s): 1952; : A5205
    Note: Project file related to Wellman House; location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Peabody "Hodgson House", / Date(s): 1952; : A5210
    Note: Project files related to Peabody "Hodgson House", Dover, MA. ER sketch for bedroom addition to pre-fabricator's base plan.
    Note: E.F. Hodgson Company, Inc., "America's First Pre-fabricator", Boston and New York.
  - Project Files: Hagar House Alterations, / Date(s): 1952, 1955, 1961, 1962, 1964; : A5216
    Note: Project files related to Hagar House; location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Peabody Aluminum Barn and Projects, / Date(s): 1952; : A5218
    Note: Project file related to Peabody Aluminum Barn and Projects, Powisset Street, Dover, MA. This is a Butler Building sited and set on foundations by ER. Shop drawings by N. E. Erecting. Also bull pen addition.
  - Project Files: Bowditch House Addition, / Date(s): 1953; : A5301
    Note: Project files related to Bowditch House Addition, 31 Fayerweather Street, Cambridge, MA. Materials; corrugated plastic.
  - Project Files: Taintor House Addition, / Date(s): 1953; : A5302
    Note: Project file related to Taintor house, Rockport, MA.
  - Project Files: Greene House Addition, / Date(s): 1953; : A5304
    Note: Project files related to Greene House Alterations, Cambridge, MA. Parkwood plastic surfaces; Resolite plastic awnings; details of wrought iron rails.
    Content: Longfellow Park Survey; related to Frost House?
  - Project Files: St. Peter's Church, / Date(s): 1953; : A5309
    Note: Correspondence file contains sketch on envelope.
  - Project Files: Podren House, / Date(s): 1953; : A5310
    Note: Details.
  - Project Files: Peabody Projects, / Date(s): 1953; : A5314
    Note: Project file related to projects on the Peabody property, Dover, MA.
  - Project Files: Smith-Petersen Kitchen Remodeling, / Date(s): --; : A5325
    Note: Project file related to Smith-Petersen remodeling; location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Johannet Landscaping, / Date(s): 1954; : A5402
    Note: Project file related to Johannet Landscaping, 77 Country Club Lane, Belmont, MA.
  - Project Files: Jackson Garage Addition, / Date(s): 1954; : A5403
    Note: Project file related to Jackson Garage; location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Wright House Alterations, / Date(s): 1954; : A5404
    Note: Project file related to Wright House addition, Ashby, MA.
  - Project Files: Greene House, / Date(s): 1954; : A5405
    Note: Project file related to Greene House, Woodstock, VT.
  - Project Files: Schroeder House Alterations, / Date(s): 1954; : A5409
    Note: Schroeder House located at 9 Follen Street, Cambridge, MA.
  - Project Files: Farnsworth Orchard Cottage, / Date(s): 1954; : A5412
    Note: Project files related to Ashby Cottage, Ashby, MA.
  - Project Files: Bradley House, / Date(s): 1954; : A5416
    Note: Project files related to Bradley House, Eaglehead, Manchester, MA. Awning windows; jalousies. Shop drawings for swimming pool.
  - Project Files: Miller House Remodeling, / Date(s): 1954; : A5417
    Note: Project file related to Miller House; location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Woodward House Remodeling, / Date(s): 1954; : A5418
    Note: Project file related to Woodward House; location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Bowman Townhouse Conversion, / Date(s): 1955; : A5503
    Note: Project files related to Bowman Townhouse Conversion, 139 Bay State Road, Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: Miller House Alterations, / Date(s): 1955; : A5505
    Note: Project files related to Miller House Alterations, 502 Hale Street, Prides Crossing, MA.
  - Project Files: Peck House Kitchen Renovation, / Date(s): 1955; : A5507
  - Project Files: Van Wyck House Kitchen Renovation, / Date(s): 1955; : A5510
    Note: Project file related to Van Wyck House; location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Ravenswood Cove Chapel, / Date(s): 1955, 1957, 1960; : A5515
    Note: Project files related to Ravenswood Cove Chapel, Western Avenue, Gloucester, MA.
    Content: Flat files contain 2 black and white photographs of exterior; 7-1/2" x 9-1/2", unmounted.
    Published in: Published in D. Cole,
  - Project Files: Olmsted Furniture, / Date(s): 1955; : A5517
    Note: Project files related to Olmsted Furniture, New Boston, New Hampshire. Sketches for a bench.
  - Project Files: Legg Sun Room Addition, / Date(s): 1955; : A5518
    Note: Project file related to Legg House, Biddeford Pool, ME.
  - Project Files: Harrison House Alterations, / Date(s): 1956; : A5519
    Note: Project file related to Harrison House, Biddeford Pool, ME.
  - Project Files: Hazard House, / Date(s): 1956; : A5520
    Note: Project file related to Hazard House, Weston, MA.
  - Project Files: Burton House, / Date(s): 1956; : A5601
    Note: Project file related to Burton House, Lincoln, MA.
  - Project Files: Manville House Alteration, / Date(s): 1956; : A5605
    Note: Project files related to Manville House Alterations, 172 Beacon Street, Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: Wayside Inn Renovation, / Date(s): 1956-1957; : A5606
    Note: Project files related to Wayside Inn renovation, Wayland, MA. This is a historic reconstruction. As-built framing plans of Inn and buildings drawn by L.C. Roy under ER's direction.
  - Project Files: Wigglesworth House Alteration, / Date(s): 1958; : A5607
    Note: Project file related to Wigglesworth House, Manchester, MA.
  - Project Files: Gardiner Townhouse Alteration, / Date(s): 1956; : A5608
    Note: Project files related to Gardiner Townhouse Alteration, 29B Chestnut Street, Boston, MA. Extensively detailed.
    Note: Ironwork: Wilson-Cole Corporation, Magazine Street, Boston.
  - Project Files: Peabody-Chase Projects, / Date(s): 1956; : A5610
    Note: Project files related to Peabody-Chase Projects, Dover, MA. This includes the Parkinson-Chase House and the Hollowell House.
    Content: Correspondence file contains yellow paper sketches.
  - Project Files: Greene Red Farmhouse Alteration, / Date(s): 1956; : A5612
    Note: Correspondence file contains sketches.
  - Project Files: Vaitses House Alterations, / Date(s): 1956-1958, 1960; : A5613
    Note: Project files related to Vaitses House Alterations, 13 Laurel Street.
  - Project Files: Meyer House, / Date(s): 1958; : A5614
    Note: Project files related to Meyer House, Somerset Street, Belmont, MA. Extensive preliminary sketches.
  - Project Files: Mc Creary House, / Date(s): --; : A5616
    Content: Correspondence file contains yellow trace sketches.
  - Project Files: Pope-Shaw Kitchen Renovation, / Date(s): 1956; : A5617
    Note: Project files related to Pope-Shaw Kitchen Renovation, 600 Beacon Street, Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: Out-Patient Department, MGH, / Date(s): 1956; : A5618
    Note: Project files related to Out-Patient Department, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: Pope Studio, / Date(s): 1956; : A5701
    Note: Project file related to Pope Studio, Manchester, MA.
  - Project Files: Bowditch House Renovation, / Date(s): 1957; : A5702
    Note: Project file related to Bowditch House library, Camden, ME.
  - Project Files: Farnsworth Addition to House, / Date(s): 1957; : A5703
    Content: Contains mis-filed sketches of Danforth Project, #5704.
  - Project Files: Danforth Cottage Alterations, / Date(s): 1957; : A5704
    Content: Correspondence file contains measured 8.5" x 11" pencil sketches. See #5703 for mis-filed drawings related to this project.
  - Project Files: Watson Residence, / Date(s): 1957; : A5705
    Content: Correspondence file contains small yellow trace sketches.
  - Project Files: McGreal House Alterations, / Date(s): 1957; : A5706
    Note: Correspondence files only; no associated drawing file.
    Content: Correspondence file contains 8.5" x 11" yellow paper sketches and sketch overlay over photograph.
  - Project Files: Hill House Alterations, / Date(s): 1957; : A5707
    Content: Correspondence file contains 8.5" x 11" sketches and measured sketch on grid paper.
  - Project Files: Reynolds House Alterations, / Date(s): 1958; : A5709
    Note: Project file related to Reynolds House, Wenham, MA.
  - Project Files: RIngelfinger House, / Date(s): 1957; : A5710
    Note: Project file related to sketches for Ingelfinger House, Argilla Road, Ipswich, MA.
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketch on grid paper.
  - Project Files: Sibley House, / Date(s): 1957; : A5711
    Note: Project file related to Sibley House, Ipswich, MA.
  - Project Files: Coolidge Summer House, / Date(s): 1958; : A5712
    Note: Project file related to Coolidge House, West Gloucester, MA.
  - Project Files: Coon House, / Date(s): 1957; : A5714
    Note: Project file related to Coon House, Gloucester, MA.
  - Project Files: Simonds House Alterations, / Date(s): 1961; : A5801
    Note: Project file related to Simonds House, Belmont, MA.
  - Project Files: Jacobson Apartment, / Date(s): 1958; : A5802
    Note: Correspondence file contains small paper sketches.
  - Project Files: Howard Housing Development, / Date(s): 1958; : A5803
    Note: Project files related to Howard Housing development, Mussel Point, Gloucester, MA.
  - Project Files: Farnsworth Projects, / Date(s): 1958, 1962; : A5804
    Note: Project files related to Farnsworth Projects at 274 Beacon Street, MA. Includes kitchen alterations.
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketches on 8.5" x 11" yellow paper.
  - Project Files: Blewer Alterations to Guest House, / Date(s): 1958; : A5805
    Note: Dorothea K. Harrison: Landscape Architect, Concord, MA.
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketches.
  - Project Files: Churchill Kitchen Remodeling, / Date(s): 1958; : A5806
    Note: Project file related to Churchill House, Plymouth, MA.
  - Project Files: Kirkwood-Milliken Project, / Date(s): 1958; : A5807
    Note: Project file related to Kirkwood-Milliken project, Winchester, MA. Correspondence file only; no associated drawing file.
  - Project Files: Rector's Study, Old North Church, / Date(s): 1958; : A5810
    Note: Project file related to Rector's study, Old North Church, Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: Fuller Remodeling, / Date(s): 1958; : A5811
    Content: Correspondence file contains 8.5" x 11" sketch.
  - Project Files: Johnson House Addition, / Date(s): 1958; : A5812
    Note: Project file related to Johnson House Addition, Exmoor Farm, Weston, MA. New wing on house on old foundation. Related to Farnsworth projects at Exmoor Farm.
  - Project Files: Staples House Alteration, / Date(s): 1958; : A5813
    Note: Project files related to Staples House Alterations sketches, Sudbury, MA. Sketches of existing and proposed work. Examples of ER's "liveable house plans."
    Content: Correspondence file contains 8.5" x 11" sketches.
  - Project Files: McClelland Barn Apartment, / Date(s): 1958; : A5814
    Note: Project file related to McClelland Barn, West Gloucester, MA.
  - Project Files: Tollnan House Addition, / Date(s): 1958; : A5901
    Note: Project files related to Tolnan House Addition, 9 Langford Street, Lanesville, Gloucester, MA.
  - Project Files: Jenny Townhouse Renovation, / Date(s): 1959; : A5902
    Note: Project file related to Jenny Townhouse, Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: Cushman Kitchen Remodeling, / Date(s): 1959; : A5903
    Content: Correspondence file contains 8.5" x 11" yellow sketches.
  - Project Files: Braeburn Club Remodeling, / Date(s): 1959; : A5904
    Note: Correspondence file contains blackline print of shop drawing.
  - Project Files: Cushman & Sears House Remodeling, / Date(s): 1959; : A5905
    Note: Project files related to Cushman & Sears House remodeling, 85 Beacon Street, Boston, MA. Sketches for historic house conversion to apartments.
  - Project Files: Power House, / Date(s): 1959; : A5906
  - Project Files: Copley Society Project, / Date(s): 1959; : A5907
  - Project Files: Henry Landcsape Project, / Date(s): 1959; : A5908
    Content: Correspondence file contains 8.5 x 11 sketches.
  - Project Files: YWCA Remodeling, / Date(s): 1959; : A5909
    Content: Correspondence file contains 8.5 x 11 sketches, layout on grid and yellow trace sketches.
  - Project Files: Kirkwood-Dupee Landscape Project, / Date(s): 1959; : A5910
    Note: Landscape Architect: Grace Kirkwood, Winchester, MA.
  - Project Files: McClelland Project, / Date(s): 1959; : A5911
    Content: Correspondence file contains yallow paper and yellow trace sketches.
  - Project Files: Barr House, / Date(s): 1959-1960; : A5912
    Note: Project files related to Barr House, Concord Heights, Haverhill, MA.
  - Project Files: Storrs House, / Date(s): 1959; : A5914
    Note: Project file related to Stevens House, Huntington, MA.
  - Project Files: Stevens House Addition, / Date(s): 1959; : A5915
    Note: Project files related to Stevens House, Huntington, MA.
  - Project Files: Dover Church, / Date(s): 1959; : A5916
    Note: Project related to Dover, MA, Church.
  - Project Files: Nichols Factory Addition, / Date(s): 1959-1960; : A5917
    Note: Project files related to Nichols Factory Addition, 48 Woerd Street, Waltham, MA.
    Content: Correspondence file contains yellow trace sketch of Ladies Lounge.
    Content: Flat file contains 1 black and white exterior photograph of entrance; 10" x 13", mounted.
  - Project Files: Dexter House Alteration, / Date(s): 1959; : A5918
    Note: Project file related to Dexter House, Ipswich, MA.
  - Project Files: Peabody Miscellaneous, / Date(s): 1959; : A5919
  - Project Files: Dexter House Alterations, / Date(s): 1959; : A5921
    Content: Correspondence file contains specifications for alterations to House on Argilla Road, Ipswich, MA, as well as documents pertaining to work at Louisburg Square, Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: Hubbard House Alterations, / Date(s): 1959; : A5922
    Note: Correpondence file contains yellow paper sketch.
  - Project Files: Vaitses House Alterations, / Date(s): 1959-1960; : A5923
    Note: Project files related to Vaites House Alterations, 15 Laurel Street. Project to connect two houses.
    Content: See projects #5613 and #5924.
  - Project Files: Vaitses House, / Date(s): 1960; : A5924
    Note: Project files related to Vaitses House; use of decorative block.
    Content: See project #5925 for mis-filed sketch.
  - Project Files: Children's Chapel at the Dover Church, / Date(s): 1960; : A5925
    Note: Project files related to the Children's Chapel at The Dover Church, Dover, MA; use of decorative block.
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketch plan on yellow trace. Mis-filed sketch from #5924 filed here.
  - Project Files: Morgan Kitchen Remodeling, / Date(s): 1961; : A5926
  - Project Files: Bowditch Townhouse Renovation, / Date(s): 1960; : A6001
    Note: Project file related to Bowditch Townhouse, Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: Vaitses Project, / Date(s): 1960; : A6002
    Content: Correspondence file contains mis-filed cost estimate for #5924.
  - Project Files: Rafferty House Alterations, / Date(s): 1960; : A6003
    Content: Correspondence files contain 8.5 x 11 sketches.
    Content: Interesting correspondence from Dr. Brae Rafferty describing the trials of the building process.
  - Project Files: Wigglesworth Kitchen Alterations, / Date(s): 1960; : A6004
    Note: Project file related to Wigglesworth House, Ipswich, MA.
  - Project Files: Forbes House Addition, / Date(s): 1960; : A6005
    Note: Project files related to Forbes House Addition, Walpole House, Manchester, MA., good sketches.
  - Project Files: Doriot Barn Renovation, / Date(s): 1960; : A6006
    Content: Correspondence files contain 8.5" x 11" yellow paper sketches.
  - Project Files: Community Center Conversion, / Date(s): 1960; : A6007
    Note: Project files related to Community Center Conversion, York Street, Aiken, South Carolina; sketches for development of 2 garages (Old Waites Motor Company buildings) into Community Center.
  - Project Files: Ellis House Alterations, / Date(s): 1960, 1961, 1963; : A6101
    Content: Correspondence files contain detail sketches.
    Content: See project #6514 for mis-filed blackline prints.
  - Project Files: Peakes House Alterations, / Date(s): 1961; : A6102
    Note: Located on Boston Post Road, Weston, MA.
  - Project Files: Babcock House Alterations, / Date(s): 1961; : A6103
    Note: Project file related to Babcock House, Belmont, MA.
  - Project Files: Churchill House, / Date(s): 1961; : A6104
    Note: Project files related to Churchill House, Juniper Road, Belmont, MA.
    Content: Contains letters for Olmsted Associates.
    Content: Contains blackline prints of Olmsted Brothers sub-division plan and proposed plot plan.
  - Project Files: Crane House Alterations, / Date(s): 1961; : A6105
    Note: Project file related to Crane House, Lincoln, MA.
  - Project Files: Damon House, / Date(s): 1961; : A6106
    Note: Project files related to Damon House, Center Harbor, Squam Lake, Holderness, New Hampshire. Land purchased from Mrs. Lawrence Churchill? Olmsted Brothers involvement - #10134?
    Content: Correspondence files contain small sketches.
  - Project Files: Adams Furniture, / Date(s): 1961; : A6107
    Note: Project file related to Adams Furniture, New York, NY.
  - Project Files: Park Projects, / Date(s): 1961; : A6108
    Note: Project files related to park projects, Dover, MA.
  - Project Files: Raymond Barn Renovation, / Date(s): 1960-1961; : A6109
    Content: Correspondence files contain 8.5" x 11" sketches.
  - Project Files: McGoldbrick Garage Renovation, / Date(s): 1961; : A6110
  - Project Files: McGoldbrick Garage Renovation, / Date(s): 1961; : A6111
  - Project Files: Thompson House Alterations, / Date(s): 1961; : A6112